Guide to the Harold Shadick papers, 1915-1992.
Shadick, Harold papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harold Shadick papers, 1915-1992.
14-13-2613
Shadick, Harold.
32.6 cubic ft.
Files, correspondence, teaching materials, letters of recommendation, memoirs, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of Harold Shadick include files relating to his career as Professor of Chinese Literature, 1946-1971, on administration of graduate study, miscellaneous teaching materials, and letters of recommendation; files as Director of the China Program, 1950-1966, on development of faculty positions, faculty, graduate students, development of the Wason Collection, relations of the Program within and outside the University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Harold Shadick was Professor of Chinese Literature at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers of Harold Shadick include files relating to his career as Professor of Chinese Literature, 1946-1971, on administration of graduate study, miscellaneous teaching materials, and letters of recommendation; files as Director of the China Program, 1950-1966, on development of faculty positions, faculty, graduate students, development of the Wason Collection, relations of the Program within and outside the University.
Includes correspondence, notes, daybooks, class lists, memoirs, and teaching materials. Also, CHINOPERL correspondence and records (Conference on Chinese Oral and Performing Literature).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Shadick, Harold.; CHINOPERL (Conference on Chinese Oral and Performing Literature).; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. China Program.
Subjects:
Chinese literature--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Professor of Chinese Literature, 1946-1971
Box 1
Series II. Director of the China Program (present East Asia Program)
Box 1-3
Series III. University and College Committees, etc.
Box 4
Series IV. Director: Inter-university Fellowships for Field Training in Chinese, 1956-1962, financed by the Ford Foundation
Box 4
Series IV. Director: Inter-university Fellowships for Field Training in Chinese, 1956-1962, financed by the Ford Foundation
Box 4-5
Series V. Director: Research Project "Linguistic Studies in Modern Chinese" commissioned by the U.S. Office of Education, 1960-1968
Box 5-6
Series VI. Participation in the Development of Chinese Studies
Box 6
Series VII. Unprocessed Material
Box 7-20
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Professor of Chinese Literature, 1946-1971
  - A. Degrees taken in Chinese Literature
    - Brown, Carolyn T. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - John C. Y. Yang (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wong Kam-ming (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Donald Holoch (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - B. Administration of graduate study and miscellaneous teaching material
    - Chinese courses registration (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Graduate applications, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Doctoral examinations (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Graduate School language examinations (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Chinese Literature applications (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Graduate applications (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Braid, Mrs. Leatrice (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Graduate applications, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Fellowship applications (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Planning graduate studies (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Literature seminar (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Graduate exams (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Chinese 301-2 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Chinese 301 (Fall 1968) English to Chinese (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Chinese 313 Philosophy and History tests - exam Jan. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Seminar - Far Eastern Studies [FES] 611-612, 1961-62: Modern China (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Notes and materials relating to lectures in FES 611 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - FES 612 Spring 1962 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Senior reading course (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Hainebach visit to the Center (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Chinese 416 poetry (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Tsing Hua Fellowship Fund Grant - $500 #4210 - Dr. Y. C. Mei, President - National Tsing Hua Univ. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Documents (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Analysis poem (with translation) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Notes on books for Classical Grammar (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Dick Bodman grad. exam under Prof. Mei (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Red poster to Dale Corson, 1971 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - C. Letters of recommendation
    - Letters of recommendation (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
- Series II. Director of the China Program (present East Asia Program)
  - A. Development of faculty positions in various disciplines
    - Appointment in Anthropology (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Economics
      - Appointment in Economics - Richard H. Moorsteen (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - K. C. Yeh (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Chao Kang (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Economics appointments - various (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Documents on P. Schran and Hou Chi-Ming (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Liu, Ta-Chung (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Nai-Ruenn Chen (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Law and Government
      - John M. H. Lindbeck (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Allen Whiting (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - Various (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Tang Tsou (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Modern History appointments (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Appointments in Chinese Literature
      - Chinese Literature (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Robert E. Hegel (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Liu, James Jo-Yu (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Ching-hsien Wang (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Ma, Yau-Woon (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Mrs. Ma Wei (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Various (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Appointment in Philosophy (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Dale Johnson (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Mason Gentzler (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Sociology appointment (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - B. Onetime faculty
    - Chow Chuen-tang (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Donald De Glopper (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Freedman, Maurice (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Frodsham, John David (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Hawkes, David (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Henry Henne (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Hockett, Charles F. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - John W. Lewis (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Marsh, Robert M. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - McCoy, William J. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Harriet C. Mills (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - David Mozingo (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Skinner, G. William (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Frederick C. Teiwes (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Treistman, Judith M. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Wang Ling (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Wolf, Arthur P. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Young, Dana B. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - C. Former graduate students
    - Chang Yu-Lung (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Miss Genevieve Dean (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Norma Diamond (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Bernard Gallin (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Harper, Paul F. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Hanson, Katherine L. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Hsu, Miss Lee L. H. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Huang, Chieh-shan (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Graham Johnson (Sociology) (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Kaplan, Paul F. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Kau, Yinmaw (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Laffey, Ella (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Landry, Richard J. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Leonard, Jane H. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - John H. Martin (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Oey, Giok Po (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Olenik, John Kenneth (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Olsen, Nancy J. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Olsen, Stephen M. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Parish, William L., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Reynolds, Sheila (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Kay Sinclair (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Anita Soysa (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Su, Tina Han (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Galal LeRoy Walker (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - James Wang (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Vicki Weinstein (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - White, Douglas G. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - D. Interdisciplinary Seminars
    - Seminars 1949-50 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Spring - seminar in Modern China, F.E.S. 612, 1961-62 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - E. Development of the Wason Collection
    - Wason Development (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Wason Acquisitions Accounts (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Wason Collection (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - Gaskill, Gussie (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Scott, Mrs. A. C. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Scott, Mr. A. C. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Ma, John T. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Richard Howard (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - William Hu (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Book Purchases - Oriental-Tien, 1946-75 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
    - Mr. John Ma's trip (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - F. Relations of the China Program within the University
    - Communications with Chairman/Department of Asian Studies (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Acting Chairman of F.E.S - Chinese Studies, 1949-50 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Acting chair F.E.S. - HRAF (Human Relation Area Files) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Asian Studies Department - annual report (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
    - Asian Studies announcements (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Communication with Dean of Arts and Sciences (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Possible structural changes in Department of Asian Studies (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - J. M. Cowan (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Center for International Studies (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
    - Draft of China Program by-laws (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Ford application - China, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Research program, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Ford Grants in Aid #4070 - China, 1959-61 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Ford application drafts, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Ford proposal, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 31-32)
    - Untitled (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Report to Ford (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - G. Relations of the China Program outside the University
    - London-Cornell Project (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - NDEA (National Defense Education Act) Center reports, 1964-65, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - NDEA (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Chinese Embassy - Huang Hua (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Cheng Hsi (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Chenoweth, Gene (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Eide, Mr. Elling O. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Li Lin-ts'an (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Prusek, Jaroslan (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Scholes, James (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Constantine Tung (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Denis Twitchett (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Wang Gung-wu (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Series III. University and College Committees, etc.
  - A. University Lectures Committee, 1957-1959
    - Lecture Committee (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Short series of lectures, 1957-58 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - B. College Committee on the Humanities, 1964-1965
    - Committee on the Humanities (Box 4, Folder 3-5)
  - C. Advisor to the Chinese Student Club, 1957-1964
    - Advisor to Chinese Student Club (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Series IV. Director: Inter-university Fellowships for Field Training in Chinese, 1956-1962, financed by the Ford Foundation
  - Annual Report for Ford Foundation - Inter-University Fellowship Program (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Ford Foundation (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Account No. 2110, 1957-58 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Monthly statements account no. 2110, 1960-61, 1961-62 (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
  - Account No. 2110, 1956-57 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with centers, 1956-59 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
  - Form letters sent to cooperating centers (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Current discussion of training and stipend problems (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Selection Committee, 1955-56 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Selection Committee, 1957-58 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Selection Committee, 1958-59 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Selection Committee, 1959-60 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Selection Committee, 1961-62 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Inter-University Program - Chinese language exams (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Stephen Tsai, 1958-59 (Box 4, Folder 23-25)
  - Chi Chia-hua Academia Sinica (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Center in Taiwan - The School (Box 4, Folder 27-28)
  - Foreign Service Institute and Bodman (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Albert E. Dien (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Mrs. Elizabeth L. Mirsky - field director of studies in Taiwan, 1960-61 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Richard T. Thompson (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Henry C. Fenn - Yale Institute (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Tunghai (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Schwartz, Henry Guenter, 1961-62 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Howard S. Levy (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Lewis, Charlton M. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series V. Director: Research Project "Linguistic Studies in Modern Chinese" commissioned by the U.S. Office of Education, 1960-1968
  - George Kuwayama, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Van Slyke, Lyman P., 1960-61 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Smythe, E. Joan, 1959-60 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sivin, Nathan (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Sheridan, James Edward (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fellowship Program and Centre in Taipei (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Inquiries regarding Inter-University Fellowship Program, also requests for application forms (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Catherine Stevens (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Kahn, Harold L. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Israel, John W., 1960-61 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Irick, Robert L., 1960-61 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Richard Campbell Howard (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Grieder, Jerome Bailey (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Applications, inquiries for 1959-60, 1960-61, 1961-62 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Two Much Trouble" (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Orientation meeting, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Terms of grant (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Chang Chi-yun (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Tests and selections, 1959-60 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Language tests, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Public relations (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Students reports (Fellows) (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Amount of grants (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Form letters to Fellows (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Announcements (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence with and about the Field (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Form letters sent to members of the Selection Committee (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Information on travel and living in Taiwan (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Catherine Steven's Project (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Winding up the Cornell Center in Taiwan and planning a seccessor - Stanford? Yale? (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Standord Center (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
  - Linguistics Studies SAE 8984 #743 - supporting documents, bills, vouchers, etc. (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Technical reports on Linguistics Studies (Box 5, Folder 39-40)
  - First course correspondence (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Recordings (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - NDEA - Linguistics Studies - account #A54 2400 (formerly #6283) (Box 5, Folder 43-44)
  - NDEA - Linguistics Studies account #7431 (#6283 eff. July 1, 1964) (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Irick, Robert L. (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Chiao, Chien (Box 6, Folder 6-8)
- Series VI. Participation in the Development of Chinese Studies
  - A.C.L.S. Sub-committee (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
  - Area Studies, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Anthology material - plan for an anthology of translations from Chinese, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Meeting of F.E.A. Program Committee, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Sino-American Conference on Intellectual Cooperation, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - MLA Advisory Committee (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
  - Columbia conference (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - MLA Committee Conference on Teaching of Chinese (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Conferences - Traditional China (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization,1963-68 (Box 6, Folder 21-24)
  - ACLS Subcommittee - Chinese Literature (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Organizing Committee meeting, Bermuda, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Conference - Genres of Chinese Literature, Bermuda, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Literature Conference, Jan. 1967 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Chinese Literature Committee Conference, 1967-69 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - New York State Education Department (and Ward Morehouse) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Biggerstaff, Knight, 1963-69 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Bodman, Nicholas C., 1961-69 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Ni, Mrs. Pei Shin (Patricia), 1960 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Nivison, David S., 1959-66 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Peterson, Charles A. (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Prof. Bertha Davis - The Ways of Man, 1968-71 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Young, Martie W., 1959-66 (Box 6, Folder 37)